Eugene Van Cleef Papers 1906-1973 Mss.Ms.Coll.61
American Philosophical Society
Eugene Van Cleef Papers
1906-1973
Mss.Ms.Coll.61
American Philosophical Society
5.0 Linear feet
A geographer from Ohio State University, Eugene Van Cleef was a specialist on Finns and Finnish immigrants to the United States, on the applications of geography to foreign trade and international commerce, and a pioneer in urban geography. The Van Cleef Papers contain 5 linear feet of personal and professional correspondence and other materials reflecting Van Cleef's varied interests in applied geography, foreign trade, and Finns. Of particular note is an autobiographical manuscript, discussing the intellectual origins of his interests in geography and giving a concise perspective on his views of the discipline.
Van Cleef, Eugene, 1887-1973
Bibliography
The Printed Materials department has a copy of one article by Van Cleef, "The Finns in Ohio," Ohio Archaeological and Historical Quarterly 43 (1934), 452-460. Call no. 977.1 Oh3.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Gift of S. Earl Brown, Professor Emeritus of Geography, Ohio State, 1989 (accn. no. 1989-596ms).
Scope and Contents note
The Van Cleef Papers contain 5 linear feet of personal and professional correspondence and other materials reflecting the research interests of Eugene Van Cleef in applied geography, foreign trade, and Finns in America. Of particular note is an autobiographical manuscript, discussing the intellectual origins of his interests in geography and giving a concise perspective on his views of the discipline.
The Van Cleef Papers are arranged in six series:
Series I. Correspondence 1909-1973 3.5 linear feet
Series II. Manuscripts 0.5 linear feet
Series III. Travel Notes and Diaries 1906-1962 0.5 linear feet
Series IV. Subject files 0.1 linear feet
Series V. Autobiographical and biographical material ca.1913-1985 0.2 linear feet
Series VI. Publication reviews 1929-1963 0.2 linear feet
Biographical/Historical note
An applied geographer from Ohio State University, Eugene Van Cleef came to his field by way of an earlier interest in meteorology. Born in Chicago in 1887, Van Cleef received his bachelor's degree in climatology at the University of Chicago in 1908 and spent much of his early career moving between positions in the corporate world and academia. After three years at Rand McNally surveying academic institutions for their interests in wall maps, he taught geography at the State Teachers College in Duluth, Minnesota from 1911-1918. In Duluth, he began to develop the first of his career constants, an interest in Finnish immigrants in the United States, and he began to develop valuable professional contacts in geography. Among the most important colleagues he cultivated at this time was the great geographer Joseph Partsch, with whom Van Cleef studied in Leipzig in 1913-1914.
During a return to the corporate world after the First World War working for his family's chemical product firm, Van Cleef acquired the second of his career constants: an interest in applying geographical knowledge to commerce and foreign trade. A talk he gave on the topic at the American Meteorological Society in December 1920 earned him an invitation to take a position as assistant professor of geography at Ohio State, where his interest in linking geography and business were well received.
Throughout his career, Van Cleef promoted the study of geography as an applied physical science, not a social science, and he assiduously sought to orient his research toward practical matters that he believed would benefit the public weal. Focusing initially on the interaction of weather, climate, and society, by the 1920s, Van Cleef's research on the Finns took on an increased momentum. He became active in a variety of humanitarian organizations focused on Finns during the 1930s, and for his efforts, he was awarded the Order of the White Rose, Commander Class II by the Finnish government.
Convinced of the need for American corporations to improve their knowledge of the world, his department asked Van Cleef to develop a geographical curriculum in international trade. His two books on the subject, Getting into Foreign Trade (1946) and Geography for the Business Man (1943), were relatively little read, but were generally useful at increasing interest within the business community in geographical issues. His high school textbook This Business World (1937; later renamed Global Geography) was more widely used.
Perhaps the most important area of interest for Van Cleef, however, was urban geography where once again he applied his interests in commerce. Based upon a course he developed in urban geography (the first in the nation), Van Cleef's book Trade Centers and Trade Routes (1937) found a ready audience in business schools, and the book is credited with introducing the terms Umland and Hinterland into American geography.
Van Cleef was honored by the National Council for Geographic Education as recipient of an award for outstanding geographic writing in non-professional journals, and received the annual award from the International Trade Committee for work in foreign trade and was made the first honorary life member of the Ohio Academy of Science. The American Geographical Society's Van Cleef Medal was established in honor of Dr. Van Cleef and his wife, Frieda Miller Van Cleef for outstanding work in urban geography. He died in Columbus on November 7, 1983.
City planning.; Finland; Finns--United States; Geography--Study and teaching; International trade; Photographs
- Series I. Correspondence, 3 lin. feet
  Scope and Contents note
  Approximately 526 folders of personal and professional correspondence. The personal correspondence is related mostly to friends and relatives, students and colleagues, but includes reactions to all aspects of Van Cleef's work. The larger portion, the professional correspondence, is related to Van Cleef's work in applied geography, and specifically to his interest in education, urban planning, foreign trade, writing, and the Finns and humanitarian matters.
  The series includes some correspondence relating to Van Cleef's publications, generally listed under the name of the individual correspondent rather than the name of the publisher or institution. The folders are filed alphabetically by the name of the correspondent.
  - Subseries A. Correspondence, 1909-1973; 36 folders
    Data collected in 1972 for a study entitled "Economic relation between cities and their immediate environment." The folders in this group are also arranged alphabetically by correspondent, with a sub-caption of the city they represent.
    - Aario, Leo, 1906-, 1946-1954 (Box 1)
    - Abler, Ronald, 1972 (Box 1)
    - Abraham, J. W., 1966 (Box 1)
    - Adams, James Truslow, 1878-1949, 1940 (Box 1)
    - Agnelli, Joseph B., 1952 (Box 1)
    - Aiken, Georgia W., 1940 (Box 1)
    - Akron (Ohio), 1966 (Box 1)
    - Allen, Glen W., 1967 (Box 1)
    - Allison, Edith Brooke, 1958 (Box 1)
    - Allix, André, 1938-1939 (Box 1)
    - Allyn and Bacon, 1937-1968 (Box 1)
    - Altio, K. F., 1933-1937 (Box 1)
      Consul General of Finland. See also: Kala, T. I.
    - American City, 1968 (Box 1)
    - American Geographical Society of New York, 1938-1970 (Box 1)
      Mentioned: Fairchild, Wilma B.; Korff, Serge A.; McCune, Shannon; Warntz, William; Wrigley, Gladys M.
    - American Meteorological Society, 1964-1973 (Box 1)
      See also: Fletcher, Lyle B.
    - American-Scandinavian Foundation, 1967 (Box 1)
      Mentioned: Harris, Miles; Spengler, Kenneth
    - American Society of Planning Officials, 1959-1969 (Box 1)
      Mentioned: Friis, Erik
    - Andrews, F. E., 1932 (Box 1)
      See also: Stollman, Israel
    - Appleton-Century-Crofts, Inc., 1936-1938 (Box 1)
      Mentioned: O'Harrow, Dennis; Stollman, Israel
    - Armstrong, Warren, 1963 (Box 1)
    - Ascah, Robert, 1972 (Box 1)
      See also: Trade Centers and Trade Routes -- publication and copyright.
    - Ashwell, Thomas, 1941 (Box 1)
      Ferrin, Dana H.; Cohan, Helen; Rapport, Samuel
    - Association of American Geographers, 1936-1970 (Box 1)
      Mayor of Columbus, Ohio. See also: Crozier, James R.; Metcalf, H. D.; Oestreicher, Robert T.; Portiman, M. D.; Rhodes, James A.; Sensenbrenner, M. E.; Gregg, Albert B.; Westlake, W. Ralston; Simon, Frederick J.
    - Avery, Edwin F., 1964 (Box 1)
    - Avison, Walter I., 1963 (Box 1)
    - Bailey, Perry, 1953 (Box 1)
      See also: Raup, H. F.; Nystrom, Warren J.; borchert, John R.; Spenser, J. E.; Clark, Andrew H.; James, Preston E.; Van Cleef Medal
    - Bailey, Walter H., 1961-1962 (Box 1)
      See also: Toledo, Ohio and Lucas County Port Authority
    - Baker, Carlyle M., [1962?] (Box 1)
    - Baldwin, Richard S., 1910-, 1966 (Box 1)
    - Barlow, Frederick J., 1969 (Box 1)
    - Barron's Educational Series, 1958-1973 (Box 1)
    - Barton, Thomas F., 1950-1965 (Box 1)
    - Bassett, Joyce, 1961 (Box 1)
      County of Los Angeles, Regional Planning Commission
    - Batt, William L., 1941 (Box 1)
    - Beall, Hayes, 1960 (Box 1)
      Journal of Geography
    - Beaton, W. S., 1950-1951 (Box 1)
    - Bendler, L. J., 1968 (Box 1)
    - Benedict, Francis, 1932-1933 (Box 1)
      Cooperative League of the USA
    - Bevis, Howard L., 1947-1950 (Box 1)
      Photograph: Sudbury, Ontario. See also: Hill, K. E.; Kolehmainen, John I., Kaye, V. J.; Kuikka, Vaino
    - Black, Elaine A., 1968-1972 (Box 1)
      U. S. Department of Commerce. See also: U. S. Department of Commerce; Corzine, Harold A.; Burgess, George; Kalstrom, G. W.; Roberts, F. L.; Roterus, Victor; Schnellbacher, E. E.
    - Blunt, B. L., 1937 (Box 1)
      Carnegie Institution of Washington: Nutrition Laboratory. See also: Hitchcock, Fred
    - Bluthgen, J., 1948 (Box 1)
      Ohio State University
    - Bobotek, Walter, 1963 (Box 1)
      Columbus Chamber of Commerce. See also: Everson, Carl M.; Knepper, William E.; Lieser, David; Martin, Rosemary; Rieley, Gordon; Roberts, Kline; Starkey, Delmar G.; Sweeney, Robert E.
    - Bogie, William P., 1965-1967 (Box 1)
      This Business World. Allyn & Bacon. See also: Bruce, Graham; Clay, J. Madeline; Keeler, Harry
    - Bohannon, E. W., 1918 (Box 1)
    - Bonner, John T. Jr., 1971 (Box 1)
    - Bonyhard, Louis, 1936 (Box 1)
      Journal of the American Bankers Association
    - Borchert, John R., 1970 (Box 1)
    - Bowers, Edison L., 1950 (Box 1)
    - Briers, Evalena, 1970 (Box 1)
      Finnish Industrial Art Exhibition
    - Brigham, Albert Perry, 1929-1930 (Box 1)
      Van Cleef Memorial Medal. See also: Association of American Geographers
    - Brooks, Charles A., 1960-1973 (Box 1)
    - Brooks, Charles F., 1958 (Box 1)
      Ohio Planning Conference. See also: Strong, Miriam
    - Brown, R. C., n. d. (Box 1)
    - Brown, S. Earl, 1970-1973 (Box 1)
    - Brown, Sidney, 1959 (Box 1)
    - Bruce, Graham, 1937 (Box 1)
    - Brunn, Stanley D., 1967 (Box 1)
    - Bucher, Walter H., 1936 (Box 1)
    - Bunge, William, 1964 (Box 1)
      This Business World. Allyn & Bacon. See also: Blunt, B. L.; Clay, J. Madeline; Keeler, Harry.
    - Burch, Kenneth M., 1967 (Box 1)
    - Burgess, George K., 1926 (Box 1)
    - Bussil, Meredith, 1941 (Box 1)
    - Butler, Richard Wayne, 1973 (Box 1)
      Greater Cincinnati Chamber of Commerce
    - Cabot, Thomas D., 1966 (Box 1)
      U. S. Department of Commerce. See also: Corzine, Harold A.; Kalstrom, G. W.; Roberts, F. L.; Roterus, Victor; Schnellbacher, E. E.; U. S. Department of Commerce; Benderler, L. J.; Marrone, Joseph M.
    - Calhoun, 1957 (Box 1)
      U. S. Department of the Interior
    - Carson, James J., 1941 (Box 1)
    - Cashman, Sam, 1954 (Box 1)
    - Cassel, Thyma (Mrs. ), 1969 (Box 1)
      Ronald Press Co. Getting into Foreign Trade
    - Chapman, E. C., 1961 (Box 1)
    - Christian Science Monitor, 1966-1968 (Box 1)
      Ohio State Fair. See also: Collinson, K. M.
    - Church, Martha, 1966 (Box 1)
    - Clark, Dean, n. d. (Box 1)
    - Clay, J. Madeline, 1937 (Box 1)
      Cobb, Priscilla M.; Dole, Charles E.; Harvey, N. Clifford; Hayward, Henry S.
    - Cleal, Harold L., 1964 (Box 1)
    - Clements, Mike, 1966 (Box 1)
    - Clyde, Paul H., 1930 (Box 1)
      This Business World, Allyn & Bacon. See also: Blunt, B. L.; Bruce, Graham; Keeler, Harry
    - Collander, P. J., 1940 (Box 2)
    - Collins, Marguerite Q., 1970 (Box 2)
    - Collison, K. M., 1959 (Box 2)
      Ohio State University Press Books; Harvey Walker
    - Columbia Broadcasting System, 1969 (Box 2)
    - Cooper, Benjamin P., 1954-1969 (Box 2)
      State Department of Industrial and Economic Development, Ohio. Ohio State Fair. See also: Cashman, Sam
    - Corzine, Harold A., 1971 (Box 2)
    - Council of the Southern Mountains, Inc., 1959-1964 (Box 2)
    - Court, Arnold, 1970 (Box 2)
    - Cowie, Jack, 1965 (Box 2)
      U. S. Department of Commerce. See also: Burgess, George K.; Kalstrom, G. W.; Roberts, F. L.; Roterus, Victor; Schnellbacher, E. E.; U. S. Department of Commerce; Bendler, L. J.; Marrone, Joseph M. Re: Monthly Weather Review
    - Cox, John M., 1963 (Box 2)
      Ayer, P. F.
    - Crosley, W. S., 1927 (Box 2)
      San Fernando Valley State College
    - Crozier, James R., 1968 (Box 2)
      State of Ohio Department of Highways
    - Dahle, Ruth D., 1939 (Box 2)
    - Daley, Arthur E., 1953 (Box 2)
      Hydrographic Office, U. S. Navy Department
    - Dally, James, 1967 (Box 2)
      City of Columbus, Ohio Department of Development. See also: Metcalf, H. D.; Oestreicher, Robert T.; Portman, M. D.; Rhodes, James A.; Sensenbrenner, M. E.; Armstrong, Warren; Gregg, Albert B.; Westlake, W. Ralston; Simon, Frederick J.
    - Davis, E. E., 1970 (Box 2)
    - Davis, Lloyd, 1950 (Box 2)
    - Davis, W. Rex, 1963 (Box 2)
      Mount Vernon Area Chamber of Commerce
    - DeChant, R. L., 1963 (Box 2)
      James A. Rhodes Historical Center
    - De Gripenberg, Peggy, 1941 (Box 2)
      Ohio National Bank; McCann, Gregory Louis
    - Demko, 1969 (Box 2)
    - Denmead, R. G., 1970 (Box 2)
      Greater Cleveland Growth Board
    - Devine, Donald F., 1968 (Box 2)
    - Devine, Samuel, 1965-1967 (Box 2)
    - DeVore, Ronald, 1966 (Box 2)
    - Dexter, Ralph W., 1964 (Box 2)
    - Doerr, Arthur H., 1962 (Box 2)
      Congressman
    - Donnelly, L. G., 1966 (Box 2)
      Councilman
    - Dorries, Hans, 1938 (Box 2)
      Ohio Academy of Science
    - Duffy, Robert H., 1973 (Box 2)
    - Duncan, Craig, 1967-1968 (Box 2)
    - Durand, Loyal Jr., 1952 (Box 2)
    - Eisen, Edna E., 1937 (Box 2)
    - Elliott, Rush, 1965 (Box 2)
    - Enarson, Harold L., 1973 (Box 2)
    - Espenshade, Edward B. Jr., 1962 (Box 2)
      Trade Centers and Trade Routes. See also: Appleton-Century [-Crofts. Corp. ]
    - Esper, Edwin A., 1966 (Box 2)
    - Evans, Lysle, 1966 (Box 2)
    - Everson, Carl M., 1948 (Box 2)
      Office of Naval Research. See also: Bailey, Walter H.; Pruitt, Evelyn L.
    - Export-Import Club, 1957-1963 (Box 2)
    - Farrell, Bryan H., 1957 (Box 2)
    - Fawcett, Novice G., 1962-1971 (Box 2)
      Columbus Chamber of Commerce. See also: Knepper, William E.; Lieser, David; Martin, Rosemary; Rieley, Gordon; Roberts, Kline L.; Starkey, Delmar G; Black, Elaine; Sweeney, Frederick J.
    - Fieandt, R. V., 1949 (Box 2)
      Knepper, William; Duarte, George
    - Finlandia Foundation, 1956-1968 (Box 2)
    - Finney, John C., 1965 (Box 2)
      Ohio State University President
    - Fisk, Peter, 1937 (Box 2)
    - Fitzhugh, Ed, 1953 (Box 2)
      See also: Paloheimo, V. A., Commissioner General of Finland
    - Fletcher, Lyle B., 1954 (Box 2)
      See also: Allyn & Bacon, Inc.
    - Fox, William Henry, 1932 (Box 2)
    - Frank, Paul, 1943 (Box 2)
      Chicago Sun Times Syndicate
    - Franklin University, 1972 (Box 2)
      American Meteorological Society. See also: American Meteorological Society
    - French, John, 1951 (Box 2)
      Brooklyn Museum
    - Friedly, Dale M., 1959-1960 (Box 2)
    - Fritsche, Ernest G., 1970 (Box 2)
    - Frye, Grace Hare, 1959 (Box 2)
      International Development Advisory Board
    - Fullen, John B., 1961 (Box 2)
    - Gainer, Nell, 1957 (Box 2)
    - Gainsborough, S., 1949 (Box 2)
      Columbus (Ohio) Town Meeting
    - Galbreath, George R., 1953 (Box 2)
      Ohio State University Organization
    - Galbreath, John W., 1964 (Box 2)
    - Galpin, Perrin C., 1940-1941 (Box 2)
    - Garner, Dewey, 1953 (Box 2)
    - Garrett, A. B., 1964 (Box 2)
    - Garrett, W. V., 1948 (Box 2)
      Finnish Relief Fund, Inc.
    - Geppert, Otto Emil, 1970 (Box 2)
    - Gerckens, Lawrence, 1965 (Box 2)
    - Gerlach, Arch C., 1953 (Box 2)
      See also: Hilden, Kaarlo
    - Gibson, J. Sullivan, 1963 (Box 2)
    - Gibson, Lyle E., 1964 (Box 2)
    - Gilland, Erna G., 1950-1962 (Box 2)
    - Gillin, John P., 1940-1945 (Box 2)
    - Gingher, Paul R., 1951-1952 (Box 2)
      California State College at Palo Verdes
    - Glander, Charles F., 1973 (Box 2)
    - Godfrey, Ernie R., 1960 (Box 2)
    - Godlund, Sven, 1952 (Box 2)
    - Gonsalves, Danny, 1969 (Box 2)
      Mayor, City of Upper Arlington. See als: Nott, Lois M.; Traphagan, Charles R.; Wells, R. C.
    - Goode, J. Paul, 1909-1929 (Box 2)
    - Goode, Kenneth, 1932 (Box 2)
    - Goss Family, n. d., November 15 (Box 2)
      Barrows, Harlan H.
    - Gowens, Norman C., 1948 (Box 2)
    - Graham, J. E., 1954 (Box xxx)
      Goode, J. Paul
    - Grano, J. A., 1931-1953 (Box 3)
    - Grano, Olavi, 1955 (Box 3)
    - Graves, Billy, n. d. (Box 3)
    - Gray, James A., 1966 (Box 3)
    - Green, E. L., 1956 (Box 3)
    - Green, Floyd F., 1951 (Box 3)
    - Greenlie, Helen Brown, 1937 (Box 3)
    - Greer, E. W., 1953 (Box 3)
    - Greer, Howard C., 1949 (Box 3)
    - Gregg, Albert B., 1954-1955 (Box 3)
    - Gregory, W. M., 1931-1955 (Box 3)
    - Griffith, Mary, 1946 (Box 3)
      See also: McClintock, Richard H.
    - Gross, Herbert H., 1967 (Box 3)
      Councilman, Columbus Ohio. See also: Armstrong, Warren; Crozier, James R.; Metcalf, H. D.; Oestreicher, Robert T.; Porman, M. D.; Rhodes, James A.; Sensenbrenner, M. E.; Westlake, W. Ralston; Simon, Frederick J.
    - Grosvenor, Gilbert H., 1917 (Box 3)
      Cleveland Public Schools, Educational Museum
    - Hale, A. M., 1939 (Box 3)
      Geography for Grown-Ups
    - Hampton, H. H., 1943 (Box 3)
    - Hansen, Jean, 1968 (Box 3)
      National Geographic Society
    - Harper and Brothers Publishers, 1947-1950 (Box 3)
    - Harper's Magazine, 1973 (Box 3)
    - Harrison, 1966 (Box 3)
      Current History Magazine
    - Hartshorne, Richard, 1939-1959 (Box 3)
      Geography for Grown-Ups, Geography for the Businessman, Tead, Ordway
    - Havens, William D., 1966-1967 (Box 3)
      Harper and Brothers
    - Hays, Wayne T., 1967 (Box 3)
    - Haywood, Gerald R., 1971 (Box 3)
    - Heckstroth, Kenneth, 1954 (Box 3)
      Columbus Association of Building Owners and Managers
    - Heiskanen, Kaarina, 1971 (Box 3)
    - Heiskanen, W. A., 1964-1965 (Box 3)
    - Herre, Mary E., 1959 (Box 3)
    - Hettner, Alfred, 1931-1938 (Box 3)
    - Hewes, Leslie, 1962 (Box 3)
    - Hildén, Kaarlo, 1933-1937 (Box 3)
      Ohio Association of Garden Clubs
    - Hill, K. E., 1950-1951 (Box 3)
    - Hill, Robert E., 1965 (Box 3)
      University of Nebraska, Department of Geography
    - Hitchcock, Fred, 1933 (Box 3)
      See also: Geographical Society of Finland
    - Hoglund, A. William, 1962 (Box 3)
      See also: Beaton, W. S.; Kolchmainen, John I.; Kaye, V. J.; Kuikka, Vaino
    - Holender-Holinski, Alfred, 1931-1933, 1942-1944 (Box 3)
    - Holmes, Leo S., 1971 (Box 3)
      See also: Benedict, Francis
    - Holmstrom, P. O., 1938 (Box 3)
    - Holzner, Lutz, 1966-1967 (Box 3)
    - Hoover, Herbert, 1940-1964 (Box 3)
      Chester, Pa. See also: Keekala, John M.; Patterson, Henry C. (Mrs. ); Jalkanen, Ralph J.
    - Hoover, Herbert Jr., 1964 (Box 3)
      American Finnish Delaware Tricentenary Committee of Ohio
    - Horst, Oscar, 1968 (Box 3)
    - Hoskins, H. L., 1948 (Box 3)
    - Hough, John N., 1941 (Box 3)
    - Hubbard, George D., 1956 (Box 3)
    - Hudson, Paul N., 1952 (Box 3)
    - Hunker, Henry L., 1967 (Box 3)
      Phi Beta Kappa
    - Huntington, Ellsworth, 1933 (Box 3)
    - Delta Sigma Pi, 1963-1973 (Box 3)
    - Instytut Baltycki (Poland), 1937 (Box 1)
      U. S. Department of the Navy. See also: Pruitt, Evelyn L.; Espenshade, Edward B. Jr.
    - Ireland, Willard, 1951 (Box 3)
    - Jackson, Douglas W. A., 1959 (Box 3)
    - Jaeger, Alfred, 1964 (Box 3)
    - Jalkanen, Ralph J., 1971 (Box 3)
      Provincial Archives, British Columbia
    - James, Preston E., 1936-1952 (Box 3)
    - Janata, Mary M. (Mrs. Rudolph Jr. ), 1961 (Box 3)
      Alfred Jaeger Periodicals
    - Japan Soryojikan (New York, N.Y.), 1968 (Box 2)
      Board of Education, Chicago; Field Museum, Chicago
    - Jarnefelt, Risto, 1936-1955 (Box 3)
      Chester, Pa. See also: Keekala, John M.; Holmes, Leo S.; Patterson, Mrs. Henry C.
    - Javits, Jacob K., 1960 (Box 3)
      See also: Association of American Geographers
    - Jefferson, Howard B., 1965 (Box 3)
      See also: Junior League of Columbus (Ohio)
    - Jefferson, Mark, 1948 (Box 3)
    - Jenkins, Frank, 1973 (Box 3)
      Senator
    - Johnson, Thomas R., 1970 (Box 3)
      See also: Clark University
    - Johnson Reprint Corporation, 1967-1971 (Box 3)
    - Johnston, H. Freeborn, 1951 (Box 3)
    - Jonasson, Olof, 1965 (Box 3)
      Ohio Manufacturer's Association. James A. Rhodes Historical Center. See also: Davis, E. E.
    - Jones, Johnny, 1954 (Box 3)
      Trade Centers and Trade Routes. Henderson, Albert; Rappaport, Frederick; Scott, Lloyd M.; Vital; Elsa M.
    - Jones, Joseph R., 1953-1955 (Box 3)
      American Geophysical Union
    - Jucius, M., 1954 (Box 3)
    - Kahle, Ellen H., 1943 (Box 3)
    - Kajava, Jrjo, 1927 (Box 3)
    - Kala, T. I., 1970-1972 (Box 3)
    - Kallir, Esther E., 1968 (Box 3)
    - Kalstrom, G. W., 1969 (Box 3)
    - Kaltenbach, Jerry, 1968 (Box 3)
      Counsul General of Finland. See also: Altio, K. F.
    - Kates, Robert W., 1968 (Box 3)
    - Kaups, Matti E., 1964 (Box 3)
      U. S. Department of Commerce. See also: Burgess, George K.; Corzine, Harold A.; Roberts, F. L.; Roterus, Victor; Schnellbacher, E. E.; U. S. Department of Commerce; Bendler, L. J.; Marrone, Joseph M.
    - Kaye, Vladimir J., 1896-, 1950 (Box 3)
      Ohio State Fair. See also: Cashman, Sam; Collinson, K. M.
    - Kckoni, Karl, 1938 (Box 3)
    - Keekala, John M., 1971 (Box 3)
    - Keeler, Harry, 1937 (Box 3)
      Canada Department of Citizenship and Immigration. See also: Beaton, W. S.; Hill, K. E.; Kolehmainen, John I.; Kuikka, Vaino
    - Kelly, M. J., 1962 (Box 3)
    - Kelso, Clarence A., 1938 (Box 3)
      See also: Holmes, Leo S.; Jalkamen, Ralph J.; Patterson Henry C. (Mrs. )
    - Kirby, Fred W., 1967 (Box 3)
      This Business World. See also: Blunt, B. L.; Allyn and Bacon; Bruce, Graham; Clay, J. Madeline
    - Kirby, Thelma Thompson, 1966 (Box 3)
      Export Trade
    - Knadler, George, 1964 (Box 3)
      Delta Phi Epsilon
    - Knepper, William E., 1964 (Box 3)
    - Kohler, Foy D., 1963-1967 (Box 3)
      Muscogee County School District (Columbus, Georgia)
    - Kolehmainen, John Ilmari, 1910-, 1937-1950 (Box 3)
    - Korsinen, Frank, 1940 (Box 3)
      Columbus Area Chamber of Commerce. See also Everson, Carl M.; Lieser, David; Martin, Rosemary; Rieley, Gordon; Roberts, Kline L.; Starkey, Delmar G.; Black, Elaine; Sweeney, Robert E.
    - Kotek, Kathryn, 1965 (Box 3)
      Deputy Secretary of State, Embassy of the United States
    - H. P. Kraus (Firm), 1968 (Box 4)
      See also: Beaton, W. S.; Hill, Karl E.; Kaye, V. J.; Kuikka, Vaino
    - Kuikka, Vaino, 1950-1951 (Box 4)
    - Kuroi, Hisashi, 1961 (Box 4)
    - Labash, Alexander, 1946 (Box 4)
      Cecere, Charles
    - Laine, Oliver H., 1940 (Box 4)